ADB or Android Debug Bridge is a command line tool that lets you communicate with an Android device.
So in fact, ADB is the most popular command line tool which we use when working with Android.
The ADB command facilitates a variety of device actions such as installing and debugging apps, and
it also provides access to a unique shell that you can use to run a variety of commands on a device.
It's a client server program that mainly includes three components.
So it has a client which sends the command.
The client runs on your development machine.
You can invoke a client from a command line terminal by issuing an ADB command, so you can invoke the
client by using this ADB command.
Once you have installed ADB in your machine and configured the path correctly for the command line terminal,
then you can use the ADB directly like this.
So the ADB command will be available in the terminal.
The second component is a daimon ADB.
So ADB daimon.
This runs commands on a device.
Daimon runs as a background process on each device.
For example, I have the emulator running here and in the command line I get into ADB Shell.
So I'm basically getting into the shell of this emulator.
And within the emulator I can run all the shell commands.
We can use the PS command to check whether the ADB is running in the emulator.
So you can just simply grep by ADB, the ADB layman, and then you can see that it's running or five
five.
That's the process ID.
The third component is a server which manages communication between the client and Daemon.
The server runs as a background process on your development mission.
ADB is included in the Android SDK Platform Tools package.
You can download this package with the SDK manager, which will install it under the SDK platform tools,
or you can even download it with aosp.
So if you have aosp already downloaded after building, it will be available under the out folder so
you can find ADB command or the ADB executable under Android SDK SDK platform tools.
So once you download the SDK, it's already there and you could just set this part in the command line
and then you can directly use ADB.
And in case if you have already downloaded the AOSP, then you have it under out host Linux x86 and
the build and then under Bing you get the ADB.
So you can use either of these.
If you have the SDK, you can use that or with Aosp, you can make use of this one.